PARTH DOSHI

+1(470)838-0620 • parthketandoshi@gmail.com • Atlanta, GA - 30338 • parthketandoshi.github.io linkedin.com/in/parthketandoshi • github.com/parthketandoshi • leetcode.com/parthketandoshi

SUMMARY

Full-stack Software Engineer with professional experience in development, deployment and maintenance of features and enhancements in diverse software products. I have worked as a developer in the UI Centre of Excellence at Zycus where I contributed to the core libraries, products, and platforms. I have a passion for programming, a knack for problem solving and an aptitude for learning.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML5 / CSS3
- JavaScript
- C / C++ / Java
- Python SOL

- Angular 8+
- React
- Bootstrap / Sass Git / BitBucket
- MongoDB
- Spring

- AWS Services
- REST Services

CI / CD

WCAG

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Georgia State University, Computer Information Systems Department

Atlanta, GA

Graduate Assistant

August 2022 onwards

Developed professor's portfolio website and conducted research on advances in digital business transformation

AVPS Technologies Inc

Alpharetta, GA

Software Engineer May 2023 - September 2023

• Implemented front-end components, microservices, back-end databases schemas, data visualization dashboards and unit tests

• Refactored legacy code base ensuring adherence to software development standards improving performance and processes

Zycus Infotech Pvt Ltd, UI Centre of Excellence

Mumbai, India

Front-end Software Engineer

January 2021 - August 2022

- Collaborated with managers and teams from 20+ products, services, and applications to deliver 80+ complex business requirements
- Undertook development and enhancement of user stories and bug fixes across 2 core libraries, 1 core product and 1 platform
- Developed and enhanced 47 front-end components for the UI component library and undertook POC tasks for the same
- Implemented 3 critical data visualization dashboards get comprehensive and granular visibility of CRMS, products and services
- Liaised with UI/UX design team as developer SPOC to audit adherence of mockups to design patterns and WCAG A11Y standards
- Implemented the UI theme, 6 launch points and 10 manifestation areas for the app store platform and its integration in products
- Upgraded language management system platform and BFF from Java 8 to OpenJDK 11 and migrated public dependencies
- Automated icon code generation and publishing process leveraging open-source tools saving 12 hours of manual effort per sprint
- · Improved reliability, maintainability, scalability, and security achieving an overall Sonar rating of A across all products
- Groomed 8 resources through knowledge sharing & knowledge transfer sessions and authored documentation on best practices

CampK12

Mumbai, India

App & Game Development Instructor

April 2020 - May 2020

Taught android app development and AR/VR game development to 47 K-12 students with an aggregate rating of 4.76 on 5

Fube Technology

Malaysia (Remote)

Front-end Developer

December 2018 - March 2019

Developed a social media platform and a video sharing web application using Firebase, Laravel, Bootstrap and MySQL

Trivia Softwares

Mumbai, India

Android & Python Application Developer

June 2018 - July 2018

Developed a healthcare android app and a student database desktop application with Oracle server back-end and Python GUI

TopprWordPress Administrator & SEO Manager

Mumbai, India February 2018 - July 2018

Developed and edited educational content, maintained SEO on the EdTech platform and collaborated with a team of freelancers

VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCES

Indian Society for Technical Education

Computer Society of India

TAPtheTECH

Teach for India

SELECTED PROJECTS

Social Media Platform - Angular web application fetching data from APIs and displaying profiles of fictional users along with their details, posts, and image gallery after logging in utilizing components from Angular Material library and hosted using Firebase

IoT Bridge Health Monitoring System - A comprehensive IoT platform for monitoring structural health of bridges comprising sensors, Python applications for Image & Audio processing, and a Progressive Web Application with authentication hosted using Firebase

EDUCATION

Georgia State University, J. Mack Robinson College of Business

Atlanta, GA

Master of Science, Computer Information Systems, Digital Innovation, GPA - 4.0

August 2023

University of Mumbai

Mumbai, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Engineering, GPA - 3.0

October 2020

PUBLICATION

^{&#}x27;Survey on IoT based Bridge Health Monitoring Systems', IJRESM, ISSN-2581-5792, Impact Factor- 5.72, April 2020